Tenants Political Action Committee (PAC); Records apap406
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Tenants Political Action Committee (PAC) Records
1997-2019
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap406
1.64 cubic ft.
This collection documents the activities of Tenants Political Action Committee (PAC), a tenants rights political advocacy and educational organization.
Content Description
This collection consists of campaign materials for candidates endorsed or vetted by the Tenants Political Action Committee (PAC), completed questionnaires submitted by political candidates to Tenants PAC, educational materials used by Tenants PAC, administrative records including financials and meeting minutes, and correspondence.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted with the exception of a small number of folders containing personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
All items in this collection were originally donated to the New York State Library in 2020 by Michael McKee. They were transfered to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2023 as this department also holds the New York State Tenants and Neighbors Records.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.
Historical Note
Founded in 1997 in New York City following a battle to renew state rent laws, Tenants Political Action Committee (PAC) educates tenant voters about issues having an impact upon them and helps elect pro-tenant candidates for office.
Tenants PAC (Political Action Committee) (New York (State); Landlord and tenant--New York (State); Rental housing--Law and legislation--New York (State); Social Activists and Public Advocates; Questionnaires; Housing policy--New York (State); Memos; Letters (correspondence)
- 20th Anniversary Celebration, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Andy Spano Campaign, 1997; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Board of Directors, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Board of Directors Meeting Minutes and Agendas (1 of 2), 1997-1998; 2000-2002; 2005-2018 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Board of Directors Meeting Minutes and Agendas (2 of 2), 1997-1998; 2000-2002; 2005-2018 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Board of Elections Filings and Verification Statements (1 of 2), 1997-2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Board of Elections Filings and Verification Statements (2 of 2), 1997-2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Candidate Interview Notes, 2001; 2005; 2016-2017; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Certificate of Incorporation, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Contributions, 1997-1998; 2000; 2006; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Doreen Banks Campaign, 1997-1998; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Endorsements and Voter Guides-RESTRICTED, 1999-2002; 2004-2005; 2012; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
- Fair Housing Coalition for People with Disabilities, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Flyers, Pamphlets, and Other Political Communications (1 of 2), 1998-2017; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Flyers, Pamphlets, and Other Political Communications (2 of 2), 1998-2017; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- General Background Research (1 of 2), 1999-2002; 2004; 2006-2008; 2012-2014; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- General Background Research (2 of 2), 1999-2002; 2004; 2006-2008; 2012-2014; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- General Correspondence (1 of 2), 1998-2016; 2018-2019; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- General Correspondence (2 of 2), 1998-2016; 2018-2019; Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Honoring Michael McKee, 2007 (Dvd 1)
- Housing Here and Now, 2006-2007; 2009-2010; Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Internal Memos, 1997-2009; 2012; Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Kenneth Zebrowski Campaign, 1997; 1999; Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Love Handles Benefit Photos, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Memo in Opposition to Bill S4899A, 2019 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Nassau - Honoring McKee, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Photos, 2001; 2005; Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Public Testimony, 2006-2007; 2011-2013; 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for Manhattan Borough President, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for New York City Council-RESTRICTED (1 of 3), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for New York City Council-RESTRICTED (2 of 3), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for New York City Council-RESTRICTED (3 of 3), 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for New York City Council (1 of 2), 2013 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for New York City Council (2 of 2), 2013 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for New York City Council (1 of 2), 2017 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for New York City Council (2 of 2), 2017 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for New York City Mayor-RESTRICTED, 2001; 2013 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for New York City Public Advocate, 2013; 2019; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for New York State Assembly, 2014-2015 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for New York State Governor, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Questionnaires for Candidates for New York State Senate, 2010; 2014; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Real Rent Reform Campaign, 2008-2015; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Rent Guidelines Board, 1998; 2003; 2005-2009; Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Senator Bill Perkins Meets with Vacancy Decontrol Advocates, 2009 (Dvd 2)
- Senator Perkins Vacancy Decontrol, 2009 (Dvd 3)
- Tom Abinanti Campaign, 2000; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Vincent Gentile Campaign, 1998; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)